你早知道了吗
Did you know?
系统崩溃
启动系统关闭
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
时间轴：sagelibra irrelevant  Jessie are being watch  迟迟will find you
翻译：SEEKING油炸电风扇  can u hear乖宝宝  wait for紫玉
[ ! ] : . / 初始化系统恢复
寻找管理员
翻译：麦结double fried  面条打包子wish had a pet
翻译：Bear the NoNopig  天朝快乐躺枪  沙沙absolutely
特效&压制：灰灰 will free you    翻译&校对&总监：阿好 always
你  能  听见  我吗
Can... you... hear... me?
当然
Absolutely.
你  能  听见  我吗
Can... you... hear... me?
是的
Yes.
三  点  钟
3 o'clock.
我明白
I understand.
来吧  哈罗德
Come on, Harold.
好戏开场了
The fun's just getting started.
这可不是接电话的好时候
Not exactly a great moment for a personal call.
四  点  钟
4 o'clock.
十一  点  钟
11 o'clock.
十  点  钟
10 o'clock.
我们得走了  里瑟  快
We need to move, Reese. Now.
-留下  -留下
- Stay. - Stay.
听我指挥
Follow my lead.
请简略音频提示
Abbreviate audio prompts, please.
确认
Confirmed.
我不习惯用数字计方向
And the numbers aren't doing it for me.
用升调表示向右
Let's try an ascending tone cue for right,
降调表示向左
descending for left.
一  点  钟
1 o'clock.
九  点  钟
9 o'clock.
威胁评估图
二  点  钟
2 o'clock.
走  快
Move now.
我们走
Let's go.
你还说我不会喜欢  哈罗德
I thought you said I wouldn't enjoy this, Harold.
不幸的是  我对机器的权限只有24小时
Sadly, though, if my access to the machine only lasts 24 hours,
该走了
it's time to go.
你朋友约翰一直死咬着我们不放
Your friend John's been keeping up with us.
怎么回事
How is that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不是在问你  哈罗德
I wasn't asking you, Harold.
追踪
你要不要告诉我你在跟谁说话  约翰
You wanna fill me in on who you're talking to, John?
我们的神仙教母吗
Our fairy godmother?
你曾从中获取情报的组织
The group you used to get your intel from.
你称之为"探索者"
You called them Research.
你前雇主称之为"北极光"
Your ex-boss called it Northern Lights.
你那位告诉我不存在
The ones your pal told me don't exist.
不  他们存在
No, they exist.
不过是"它"  而非"他们"
They're just an "It" rather than a "Them".
一台机器
A machine.
你是说人工智能
You mean an AI?
你的追踪器
Your tracker.
也许芬奇  不想被找到
Maybe Finch doesn't want to be found.
给我芬奇的地址
Give me a location on Finch.
你几乎无所不知
You know almost everything that's happening,
却不肯告诉我我唯一想要的
and you won't tell me the one thing I need?
好了  我今天已经帮你越狱了
Okay, look, I already broke you out of jail tonight.
我可不要再去精神病院救你
I'm not springing you from the funny farm.
好吧
Fine.
弄辆车给我们用行吧
How about a car we can use?
九  点  钟
9 o'clock.
再讲遍你的故事  警探
Tell us your story again, Detective.
这不是故事  而是事实
It's not my story. It's what happened.
嫌犯出现了  他手持武器
The suspect emerged. He had a weapon.
我就开枪将其击毙
I fired on him with lethal force.
我不知道嫌犯的武器去哪里了
I don't know what happened to the suspect's weapon.
你这样对自己可没好处  警探
You're not helping yourself, Detective.
我们二十分钟后再继续
We'll start again in 20 minutes.
所以根想获取机器的权限
So Root wants access to this machine.
她说她想放它自由
She says she wants to set it free,
要做到这点  她得先找到它
but to do that, she has to find it first.
注意
Attention.
分类: 无关号码
等等  这跟芬奇根本无关  是吧
Wait, this doesn't have anything to do with Finch, does it?
走吧  车在哪儿
Let's go. Where is this car?
分类: 无关号码
暴力可能性: 非常高
时限:
马上
好吧
Fine.
我们得稍停一下
We're gonna need to make a pit stop.
有人需要帮助
Someone needs our help.
那"人工智能天启阻止"任务呢
And the whole "Prevent the AI Apocalypse" thing?
你喜欢挑战  肖
You like a challenge, Shaw.
我们是好人  所以我们得两者兼顾
We're the good guys, which means we have to do both.
会话分析
语言识别
你没付赎金  惹怒兄弟帮的人就是这下场
别动  警察马上就到
Don't move. The cops will be here soon.
明白吗
Understand?
行了没
Are we done?
行了
We're done.
我们需要一辆新车
We're gonna need another vehicle
还有撤离路线
and a way out.
这次  要辆快点的
This time, ask for something fast.
机器说就是这辆
The machine says this is the one.
最好别又是旅行车
This better not be another station wagon.
这是干嘛
What's this for?
略解我驾车时你的心理失衡
To help you feel less inadequate while I drive this thing.
计划是什么
What was the plan?
你想杀人
You wanted to kill people.
但我们抓住了你
But we got you.
阻止了你
Stopped you.
所以无所谓了
So it doesn't matter now.
还是跟我说说吧
May as well talk to me.
港口  跟我说说港口的事
The ferry. Tell me about the ferry.
怎么花了这么长时间
What took you so damn long?
我身上到底没有定位设备
Do I or do I not have a locator beacon?
主控者认为德西玛更紧要
Control felt the Decima situation took priority.
我们要对付数名孤胆特工
And we have an ongoing situation with some rogue operatives,
包括你的前助理
including your former executive assistant.
我们担心"北极光"可能已经暴露了
We're concerned Northern Lights might have been compromised
她甚至可能获取了完整权限
and that she might even have full access.
真是天大的坏消息
This is very bad news indeed.
启动一号应急预案
We go to Contingency One.
不许用手机  避开所有摄像头
No cell phones. Avoid all cameras.
追踪主体
失去信号
改变任务
寻找管理员
你的机器正在向我描述这些人  哈罗德
Your machine is telling me about all these people, Harold,
描述他们的秘密
their secrets.
我开始明白为什么你
I'm beginning to understand how you acquired
对人性如此悲观了  哈罗德  等等
such a dim view of humanity, Harold. Wait.
我真失礼
How rude of me.
我终于看清这世界了  你却瞎了
I can see for the first time, and you're blind.
我们得给哈罗德找副眼镜
We'll need some glasses for Harold.
你肯定知道他的度数
I'm sure you know his prescription.
三  点  钟
3 o'clock.
如何
How's that?
我还是不知道这是要去哪儿
I still don't know where we're going.
你知道的
Yes, you do.
我们要去找到你的机器
We're going to find your machine.
还撑得住吗  卡特
You holding up okay, Carter?
给
Here.
-谢了  -没事
- Thanks. - It's okay.
我的口供录完了
So I made my statement.
不知道还能做什么
I don't know what else to do.
还是找不到武器
Still no sign of the weapon.
你真该联系下你的工会代表了
You really ought to contact your union rep.
不
No.
我不会有事
I'll be fine.
我知道是谁拿走了武器
I know who took the weapon.
我认出了犯罪现场的一个人
I recognized one of the unis at the crime scene.
他曾因HR案受过调查
He was questioned in the HR's thing,
但脱身了
but they let him go.
得让弗斯科跟他聊聊
Gonna have Fusco have a little talk with him.
你一直都有这个毛病  卡特
That's always been the problem with you, Carter.
你
You--
你从来不明白
you just never figured out
什么时候该闭嘴
when to keep your big mouth shut.
你跟我关系一直不错  卡特
Listen, you always been okay to me, Carter.
说实话  我也不喜欢杀女人
And frankly, I don't like killing women.
你再查下去
You keep digging,
我们就得对你动手了
we're gonna put you in the ground,
就像你男朋友一样
just like we did to your boyfriend.
你把你那惊魂未定的肮脏搭档拉进来
You drag your recovering dirtbag partner into this,
我们就连他一起收拾
we will pull the rip cord on him too.
或许还有  你的孩子
And maybe... your kid.
现在  能不能帮你自己个忙
Now...are you gonna do yourself a favor
老实坐着  乖乖接受
and sit here and take it?
这样才是好孩子
That's a good girl.
强制配对
雷蒙德・特尼
完成
老大  不  她不会再惹麻烦了
Boss. No, she's not gonna give us a problem.
下一步  我们会杀死以利亚的左右手
Next up, we kill Elias's right-hand man.
然后就轮到他本人了
Then we get the man himself.
我打了电话给几个朋友
I called in a couple of favors.
今晚会转监
Prison transfer tonight.
小熊呢
Where's Bear?
跟里昂在一起
Staying with a guy named Leon.
没想到你会喜欢那狗
Didn't think you even liked the dog.
岂止喜欢  他是我留下的唯一理由
Like him? He's the only reason I'm sticking around.
为什么来这里
Why are we here?
因为机器说在这里
Because the machine said this is
我能找到答案
where I'll find the answer.
什么问题的答案
What was the question?
机器的位置何在
Where the machine is located.
它不能直接告诉你吗
Can't it just tell you?
我想芬奇编程禁止了  以保护它
I think Finch programmed it not to, to protect it.
无意冒犯
No offense.
不过或许芬奇想自己控制机器
Maybe Finch wants control of the machine himself.
就算芬奇跟病毒有关
If Finch had something to do with the virus,
也肯定有他的理由
I'm sure he had his reasons.
反过来说  这样机器
On the upside, hopefully the machine
也不会告诉根它在哪里
won't have told Root where it is either.
下次让我见到这女人
Next time I see that woman,
我就直接开枪
I'm shooting her.
可不打膝盖
And not in the knee.
魂灵  阿尔法  千克
"Ghost Alpha Kilo."
什么东西
What's that?
一本书
A book.
库斯勒《机器中的魂灵》
开科技公司的
That's the tech guy.
奈森・英格拉姆
Nathan Ingram.
起点
奈森・英格拉姆
他和芬奇一起工作吗
He worked with Finch?
他们一起造了机器
They built the machine together.
后面有东西
There's something back there.
知道密码吗
Any guess for the combination?
她们是谁
Who are they?
不认识
I don't know.
他们曾帮助过的人
People they helped.
他们曾试图
People they tried--
你认识她
You knew her.
在乎她
Cared about her.
还活着吗
Is she alive?
不
No.
这不是芬奇的笔迹
This isn't Finch's handwriting.
肯定是英格拉姆也在找机器
Ingram must have been looking for the machine too,
在他们把机器交给政府之后
after they gave it to the government.
内华达州丝兰山
Yucca Mountain in Nevada.
华盛顿州汉福德  德克萨斯州科曼奇峰
Hanford, Washington. Comanche Peak, Texas.
他把范围缩小到这三个地方
He narrowed it down to those three places.
你知道这些有什么共同点吗
You know what they've got in common?
都是政府安全据点
They're all secure federal sites.
用来存储核燃料
For nuclear fuel storage.
根逼供我的时候
When Root was torturing me,
她想知道一位名叫丹尼尔・阿基诺的工程师
she wanted to know about an engineer named Daniel Aquino.
核工程师
A nuclear engineer.
他肯定是知道某些
He must have had something to do with
跟机器存放地点有关的事
the facility the machine is stored in.
根想要知道什么
What did Root want to know?
雇他参与"北极光"项目的人叫什么名字
The name of the man who hired him for Northern Lights.
那他叫什么名字
And what was his name?
劳伦斯
Lawrence.
劳伦斯・西拉德
Lawrence Szilard.
真高兴终于见到你了  劳伦
Nice to finally meet you, Larry.
我有问题要问
I've got some questions.
你想怎样  哈罗德
What do you want, Harold?
你几天都没来办公室了
You haven't been in the office for days.
你不回我电话
You won't return any of my calls.
我不干了
I quit.
我知道你在寻找机器
I know you've been looking for the machine.
奈森  如果你想重新
Nathan, if you're trying to get back in
获取无关号码
to access the irrelevant numbers--
没用的  我知道  你把我封锁在外了
It won't work, I know. You locked me out.
你当工程师一直比我高明
You were always the better engineer.
但我有一项超过你的优势
But I do have one advantage over you.
我是IFT公司的对外负责人
I am the face of IFT,
如果我打电话约记者出来喝杯咖啡
which means when I call a reporter to meet me for coffee,
记者就会来
he'll be there.
你打算做什么  奈森
What are you going to do, Nathan?
我要说出我们所做的
I'm going to tell them what we did,
我们所造的
what we built.
-不  你不可以  -为什么
- No, you can't do that. - Why?
因为政府会关闭它
Because the government will shut it down?
因为大局为重  我受够这些了
Because of the greater good? I'm sick of hearing it.
不  不仅如此了
No, it's not just that anymore.
我查过了
I've been looking into this.
我认为政府在追杀他们
I think the government may be killing them.
考文安排了很多工程师重新组装
The engineers that Corwin had reassemble
我们运走的机器
the machine after we shipped it off?
那些人有的出意外  有的失踪
There have been accidents, disappearances.
项目的主管  名叫劳伦斯・西拉德
The head of the project, a man named Lawrence Szilard,
上个月失踪了
went missing last month.
哈罗德  你逃了太久  成惊弓之鸟了
Harold, you have been running so long, it's rattled you.
艾丽西娅不会害我的
Alicia isn't going to have me bumped off.
她可能根本就控制不了
It might be out of her control.
我们给了政府终极权力
We gave the government the ultimate power.
如果他们知道你打电话给记者
If they know you've called a journalist,
他们绝对不会放过的
they won't take any chances.
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you
以及可能知道此事的所有人
and anybody else they think might know about it.
你从不相信任何人
You've never trusted anyone.
不相信我  不相信机器
Not me, not the machine.
你告诉未婚妻你的真名了吗
Have you even told your fiancee your real name yet?
我在等适当的时机
I'm waiting for the right moment.
奈森  求你
Nathan, please,
告诉我要怎样才能阻止你
tell me what I can do to stop you.
把无关名单还给我
Give me back the irrelevant list.
你甚至可以帮我
You could even help me.
怎么  你我就坐在这儿
What, you and me sitting here,
试图一个个拯救他们吗
trying to rescue them one at a time?
现在就有号码在名单中了
Someone's number's on that thing right now.
到午夜就会被删掉
It's gonna be erased at midnight.
或许  或许我们能帮助他们
Maybe... maybe we can help them.
我不想要帮助他们
I'm not trying to help them.
我只想要帮助你
I'm trying to help you.
34街客运港口
34th Street Ferry Terminal.
明早八点
8:00 am tomorrow.
该说出我们的故事了
It's time we tell our side of the story.
你应该到场
You should be there.
我们得聊聊  劳伦斯
Time for a chat, Lawrence.
你怎么找到我的
How did you know where to find me?
就算是朋友告诉我的吧
Let's say a friend told me.
你们是谁  想要什么
And who are you? What do you want?
我们想知道"北极光"的事
We wanna know about Northern Lights.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
无可奉告
I have nothing to say.
你女儿  克里斯汀
Your daughter, Christine.
你把她藏在洛杉矶
In LA where you hid her.
要是负责"北极光"的人抓住她就不好了
Such a shame if people running Northern Lights got hold of her.
拜托  没必要这样
Please, there's no need for that.
我可以告诉你开头
I can tell you how it began.
有个名叫艾丽西娅・考文的女人来找你
You were approached by a woman named Alicia Corwin.
她去年被杀了
She was killed last year.
真是悲剧啊
Such a tragedy.
做那项目的所有同事都在
All of my colleagues on that project
过去两年离奇死去
died in suspicious circumstances in the past two years.
据我所知  我是唯一活着的
As far as I know, I'm the last one alive.
你是唯一能
And you're the last person
告诉我们"北极光"信息的
who can tell us about Northern Lights.
西拉德在中央公园
Szilard's in Central Park.
应该能在那里找到芬奇
Guessing that's where we're gonna find Finch.
分类: 无关号码
又得稍停一下
Another pit stop?
你们多久收到一次号码
How often do you guys get a number?
有时候  一天都没有
Some days, none.
看起来今天不是那种日子啊
Doesn't seem like today's gonna be one of those days though.
我们走
Let's go.
我说过如果我得不到你  别人也别想
I told you if I can't have you, no one will.
别想  卡蒂
No one, Katie.
别想
No one.
恭贺新婚
Congratulations.
我们承包建造一栋建筑
We were contracted to build a structure.
它要能隐身于众目睽睽之下
It had to be hidden in plain sight
还要能提供足够五万人用的能源
and have power for 50,000 people.
一开始  我说  "当是玩笑吧
At first, you know, I said, "That's a joke.
建个核反应堆怎么样"
What about a nuclear reactor?"
第二天  我就收到了
The next day, I was given
核设施的工程设计书
specs for a nuclear reprocessing facility
还有前来施工的陆军工兵部队
and the Army Corps of Engineers as a work force.
接着它陆续到达了
And then it started to arrive
伪装成放射性物质以避开审查
disguised as radioactive material to evade scrutiny.
我们只被告知  插上电源
We were just told to-- to plug it in.
剩下的他们搞定
They would take care of the rest,
不过我一直好奇心旺盛
but I've always been the curious type.
于是你偷看了数据
So you took a look at the data.
只是输入输出端  其余都被加密了
Just the I/O. The rest was encrypted.
但是我看到的
But what I saw...
就像是窥见了未来
it was like a glimpse of the future.
优雅  敏锐
Elegant, intuitive.
宛如生命
Practically alive.
它正在跟你通话  是吗
It's speaking to you right now, isn't it?
走  快  多重  威胁
Move now. Multiple threats.
跟我们走
Come with us.
告诉我  "北极光"在哪儿
Tell me, where is Northern Lights?
-你不会伤害它吧  -绝不会
- You're not gonna harm it. - Never.
-我想放它自由  -很好  当然
- I want to set it free. - Good. Of course.
不
No.
现在收拾那女人
Now take the woman.
它在哪里  拜托
Where is it? Please.
走  快走
Let's go. We have to go.
快
Come on.
他们杀了他  哈罗德
They murdered him, Harold.
他是我们最好的机会  现在该怎么办
He was our best chance. How will we find it now?
紧迫  威胁
Imminent threat.
你们敢碰他
Don't you touch him.
是她干的吗
Did she do this?
不  是你的旧雇主
No, your old employers did.
这边
This way.
先走  我随后就到
Go-on. I'll catch up with you.
退后
Stay back.
芬奇
Finch!
好了  够了
All right, enough.
我知道它在哪
I know where it is.
我带你去
I'll take you to it.
看来你朋友变心了
Looks like your friend had a change of heart.
港口  跟我说说港口的事
The ferry. Tell me about the ferry.
你原本打算干嘛
What were you going to do?
塞姆汀塑胶炸药
Semtex.
装到小货车上
Loaded on a van.
停在自由岛港口旁边
Park it next to Liberty Island ferry.
用什么引爆
How would you detonate?
我
Me.
我就是引爆装置
I am the detonator.
自杀式炸弹
Suicide bomb.
我在西拉德的手提箱里找到这个
I found this in Szilard's briefcase.
行李托运牌
Baggage claim ticket for a trip
四年前飞往俄勒冈州波特兰的
to Portland, Oregon, four years ago.
波特兰机场最靠近
Portland's the nearest airport to the nuclear fac--
华盛顿汉福德核设施
To the nuclear facility at Hanford, Washington.
那是西拉德曾经工作的地方
That's where Szilard worked.
那是"北极光"的所在地
That's where northern lights is.
所以那是根要去的地方
So that's where Root's headed.
警察执行公务  女士
Police business, Ma'am.
给我看你的警徽
Let's see your badge.
纽约人啊
New Yorkers.
我正要上车
I'm getting in the car now.
40分钟后起飞
Wheels up in 40.
飞往圣巴特斯岛
Flight plan for St. Barts.
我相信这时节的小岛风光一定很美  钱德勒先生
I'm sure the islands are lovely this time of year, Mr. Chandler,
但我和朋友需要你的飞机带我们去波特兰
but my friend and I need your jet to take us to Portland.
卡特  我一直很担心  你还好吗
Carter, I've been worried. You okay?
好点儿了  不过那个不急
I've been better. But, look, that can wait.
我认为HR和约格洛夫一伙
I think HR and Yogorov's crew
今晚要带走以利亚
are gonna take out Elias tonight.
以利亚曾想杀了你  乔丝
Elias tried to kill you, Joss.
他绑架了你儿子
He kidnapped your son.
他的幸福安康可不是我的紧要大事
His well-being isn't exactly a priority for me.
他的副手今早中枪了
His lieutenant was gunned down this morning.
以利亚的第一反应就是安排他的保镖假释
The first thing Elias did was get his bodyguards paroled
去医院照顾他的手下
to watch his man in the hospital.
至少他忠诚守信
At least he's loyal.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
抱歉乔丝  我得挂电话了
Sorry, Joss, gotta go.
拜托低调点
Please just keep your head down.
你也是  虽然我知道你做不到
You too. Though I know you won't.
你叫那玩意儿带我们逃出去
You tell that thing to get us out of here...
否则我就用我的方法来了
unless you want me to end this chase my way.
你听到了  麻烦找出路
You heard her. Exit routes, please.
300  码  转右
300 yards right.
右边没路
There is no right.
200  码  转右
200 yards right.
200码后转右
In 200 yards, turn right.
哪个右  约翰
What right, John?
有点信心  肖
You gotta trust, Shaw.
100  码  转右
100 yards right.
会有点儿颠簸
This is gonna be a rough landing.
借直升机一用  各位
Need to borrow your helicopter, fellas.
到头了  以利亚
End of the road, Elias.
原来是这种转监啊
That sort of prisoner transfer.
我听说了你的故事  以利亚
Heard a story about you, Elias.
你老爸想要干掉你
Your daddy wanted to put you down.
于是他让两个手下把你带到了树林里
He had two of his goombahs take you for a walk in the woods.
这故事有什么寓意吗
Does this story have a moral?
有  一报还一报
Yeah. What goes around comes around.
不  你没资格跟我说话
No. You don't get to talk to me.
我忠于自我
I'm true to what I am.
就像这位朋友约格洛夫先生
Like my friend Mr. Yogorov here.
我杀了他父亲  他要杀我
I killed his father. He kills me.
很公平
Fair is fair.
但你  你背弃承诺
But you, you're a-- you're an oath breaker.
可怜虫一只
You're a worm.
我看你说够了
I think that's enough of you.
废物
Piece of crap.
饶命  饶命  我还有家人
Please, please, I got a family.
卡特警探
Detective Carter.
世界真奇妙啊
What a funny old world.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
我不知道
I don't know.
追踪管理员
汉福德核测验设施
目的地: 高度机密
汉福德
无信号
四号安全壳系统故障
Breach in containment system four.
切换为应急系统
Switching to emergency override.
所有人马上离开
Everyone leave now.
密码
Code.
键盘密码
Keypad code.
管理员权限
失效
看来我们的马车变回南瓜了  哈罗德
It looks like our carriage has turned back into a pumpkin, Harold.
不过无所谓  我们到了
Doesn't matter. We made it.
你们不能进来  快离开
You can't be in here. You have to leave now.
-你们当自己是  -开门
- What do you think you're-- - Open the door.
你疯了吗  你会害死所有人
Are you crazy? You'll kill us all.
不  只会害死你
No. Just you.
来吧  哈罗德
Come on, Harold.
去会会上帝
Time to meet God.
请勿期待过高  格罗夫斯女士
Please don't set your hopes too high, Ms. Groves.
你们不能进来
You're not allowed in here.
我说了你们不能进
I said you're not allowed in--
它在哪儿
Where is it?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你说过想放机器自由
You said you wanted to set the machine free.
我已经放了
I already did.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
求你说话啊
Please talk to me.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
我相信你
I believed you.
我信任你
I believed in you.
格罗夫斯女士
Ms. Groves--
我叫根
My name is Root.
哈罗德
Harold.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
这是你所预想的吗
Is this what you expected?
这是我所希望的
It's what I hoped.
音频拦截  已修改
主题  已修改
会话分析
语言识别
我们那位朋友准备向媒体公开
Our friend is going to talk to the press.
我们绝不能允许
We can't allow that to happen.
他是公众人物
He's a public figure.
让他失踪会有麻烦
Making him disappear will be complicated.
看来我们手头有解决方案
It seems to me we have the solution in hand.
自由岛港口
下一班将于十分钟后起航
The next island ferry will be leaving in ten minutes.
所有乘客
All passengers...
阿希夫  醒醒
Asif. Come on.
该醒醒了
Time to wake up.
恭喜你  阿希夫
Congratulations, Asif.
你完成了你的任务
You've completed your mission.
哈罗德
Harold!
我知道你会来的  我的朋友
I knew you would come, my friend.
我们一起面对
Time for us to face the music.
敢回头  就吃子弹
Turn around, you get a bullet.
不是你自己做的吗
You didn't do this yourself?
我做不到  我把自己封锁在外了
I couldn't. I'd locked myself out.
机器被设计成只有在受到攻击时
The machine was designed to accept alterations
才能更改自己的程序
in its programming only as a response to an attack.
我知道迟早有一天
I knew that sooner or later
会有人想要占有它
someone would try to take it over,
但我不知道会是谁
but I didn't know who.
所以我得确保他们下手时
So I made sure that when they did
会用到我的代码
they'd do it with my code.
你在病毒之中隐藏病毒
You hid a virus within a virus?
我意识到奈森和我
I realized that the people Nathan and I
将机器托付给了错误的人
had entrusted the machine to were the wrong people,
唯一能够保护它的方法
and that the only way to protect it
就是教它保护自己
would be to teach it to protect itself.
我本无意让你卷入此事  里瑟先生
I didn't want to involve you in this business, Mr. Reese,
因为我原本希望  如果我回不去
because I had hoped that, if I hadn't returned,
你能继续我们未竟的事业
you would continue what we had started.
听上去不妙
That's not good.
我们该走了
We should go.
带她一起
She comes too.
如果留下她  他们会杀了她
If we leave her, they'll kill her.
肖
Shaw.
你杀我时应该下手更利索点儿  赫什
You should have killed me better, Hersh.
我知道比起眼前的
I know it's a minor matter compared to
灾难性的场景  这点不值一提了  不过
the total and utter catastrophe I'm looking at here, but...
我还以为你不会当叛徒  肖
I didn't think you'd turn traitor, Shaw.
在这种局势下  说这话可过分了
That's a strong word to be throwing around given where we're standing.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
和你的新朋友聊几句
A word or two with your new friend.
我就知道英格拉姆背后有人
I always knew there was someone behind Ingram.
就像黑洞一样
Like a black hole.
无形  却强大
Invisible, but powerful.
告诉我  你把机器搬去哪儿了
So tell me, where did you move the machine?
它自己搬走了
It moved itself.
那是谁在控制它
But who controls it?
目前  它在自我控制
As of now, it controls itself.
那些号码  它会继续给我们吗
The numbers, will they continue to come to us?
那要由机器决定
That will be up to the machine.
如果不能继续
If they don't start up again,
我们国家就将毫无防御
the country is defenseless.
不  只是防御稍弱罢了
No, just less well-defended.
我想我们彼此都明白现在的危机
I think we both understand that what's at stake here
已经超出了国家防御范围
has moved beyond simply defending the country.
是吗
Has it?
你为我们制造机器来保护人民
You built the machine for us to use to protect people.
我们做到了  做得很好
We do, very well.
不要跟我们对抗
Don't fight us.
帮我们找回来  或者再造一个
Help us recover it or rebuild it.
你提什么要求都行
You can dictate your terms.
我向你保证
You have my word.
你向我的朋友保证过
You gave my friend your word.
而你杀了他
And you killed him.
我们走
We're leaving.
你以为你站对边了吗  肖
You think you're choosing the right side, Shaw?
真的吗
Really?
你也骗过我
You lied to me too.
奈森
Nathan.
Nathan!
别动
Don't move.
你遇上了事故
You've been in an accident.
我要找我的朋友
I have to find my friend.
先生  请你躺着别动  好吗
Sir, I just need you to lie still for me, okay?
你的颈部和腰部受了伤
You've sustained injuries to your neck and lower back.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
医生  快
Doctor, quickly.
别动  我马上回来
Don't move. I'll be right back.
检查颈动脉
Check the carotid.
我宣布死亡时间为
I'm calling it. TOD...
奈森
Nathan?
搞定了
It's done.
我们去查他是否和别人谈过
We'll find out if he talked to anyone
一并解决
and take care of them too.
哈罗德
Harold?
请帮帮我  我的未婚夫可能在港口
Help, please. I think my fiance was on the ferry.
-你知道他在  -抱歉
- Do you know where-- - I'm sorry.
我们从水里救出的所有人都在这里
This is everybody we pulled out of the water.
如果你没找到他
If you don't see him,
我们找到的个人物品在那里
the personal effects we recovered are over there.
你早知道了吗
Did you know?
显示无关号码
无关
删除无关号码
它怎么搬走的
How did it get moved?
完全根据您的指示
Exactly as you instructed.
过去五周
Over the last five weeks,
每次一个节点  所以从没下线过
one node at a time, so it was never off-line.
装在集装箱里当成核燃料被运走
Moved from here in containers marked for fissile materials.
搬去哪儿  我就不知道了
To where, I have no idea,
我还以为是故意的
which is what I thought was the point.
你就没想打电话确认一下吗
You didn't think to call to confirm?
我打了  您确认的
I did call. You confirmed it.
我们会找到的  夫人
We'll find it, Ma'am.
那么大的东西  我们会有办法追踪
With something that large, we'll find a way to track it.
我肯定
I'm sure--
是  夫人
Yes, Ma'am.
我会封锁住
I'll seal the room.
好吧
Fair enough.
芬奇  你觉得我们还会拿到号码吗
Finch, you think we'll ever get another number?
我不知道
I don't know.
里瑟先生  我欠你个解释
Mr. Reese, I owe you an explanation,
以及道歉
and an apology.
三年前
Three years ago,
我为了放机器自由而泄露代码时
when I put the code out there to free the machine,
完全不知道其途径
I had no idea what path it would take
也不知道可能因此产生的后果
or what unintended consequences it might have.
我从未想伤害任何人
I never intended to hurt anyone,
但我明白有人可能会受伤
but I accepted that someone might get hurt.
我一直在担心我所引发的
I always worried that events that I had set in motion
可能改变了你的人生
may have changed things for you.
我的生活改变于
My life changed
七年前我在航站楼保持沉默时
when I kept my mouth shut at an airport terminal seven years ago.
你与此毫无关系
You didn't have anything to do with that.
你失去了朋友
You lost a friend.
你做了你该做的
You did what you had to do.
既然号码停了
Since the numbers have stopped,
你再这么慷慨给钱我就不合适了
it's not right you should go on paying me as generously as you are.
我给你的钱90%你都捐了
Since you give away 90% of what I pay you,
我没理由不继续
I don't see why I shouldn't continue.
夫人  探索者两分钟前联系我们了
Ma'am, Research made contact two minutes ago.
是个号码
A number.
准备好队伍
Get a team ready.
精神病院
你  能  听见  我吗
Can... you... hear... me?
当然
Absolutely.